Guide to the Eunice Johnson Collection on Timothy Richard)
Yale University Divinity School Library
Eunice Johnson Collection on Timothy Richard
1867-2002
RG 232
Yale University Divinity School Library
8
(19 boxes)
This collection is comprised primarily of research materials collected by Eunice Johnson in her study of Timothy Richard (1845-1919), a Welsh Baptist missionary, statesman, and educator who spent forty-five years in China. The collected resources were used by Eunice Johnson in the writing of her Ph.D. dissertation, "Educational Reform in China, 1880-1910: Timothy Richard and his Vision for Higher Education." The collection includes photocopies and some originals of writings by and about Timothy Richard, as well as information about China during the time period when Timothy Richard was active there. The collection also includes memorabilia from the Centennial Celebration of Shanxi University (1902-2002), of which Timothy Richard was a co-founder.
Johnson, Eunice V.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Eunice Johnson
Conditions Governing Access
Open to qualified researchers.
Biographical / Historical
Eunice Johnson received her Ph.D. from the Graduate School of the University of Florida in 2001. Her dissertation was entitled, "Educational Reform in China, 1880-1910: Timothy Richard and his Vision for Higher Education". This collection is comprised of the resource materials she collected in the course of writing her dissertation. Timothy Richard (1845-1919) was born in Wales. He was first sent to China in 1869 by the Baptist Missionary Society. He spent 45 years in China as a missionary, philanthropist, missionary statesman, scholar, educator, and author.
Scope and Contents
This collection contains photocopies, originals, and microfilm of primary and secondary source materials collected by Eunice Johnson in the course of her research projects related to Timothy Richard, as well as some of her own writings. Also included is memorabilia from the Centennial Celebration of the University of Shanxi (1902-2002).
Series I, Timothy Richard Correspondence and Writings, is divided into two subseries: Correspondence and Writings. Correspondence is arranged alphabetically and includes Richard's correspondence with organizations and individuals. Writings includes photocopies of two diaries kept by Richard, hand-written notes, newspaper and journal articles, pamplets, and books written by Richard. The writings are listed by title and arranged chronologically.
Series II, Collected Research Resources, is divided into three subseries: material Related to Mary Richard (wife of Timothy Richard), material Related to Moir Duncan (colleague of Timothy Richard), and Writings Related to Timothy Richard. The material related to Mary Richard includes writings by Mary Richard and obituaries and memorials of Mary Richard. The material related to Moir Duncan, a colleague of Timothy Richard who worked with him in China, includes transcriptions of letters written by Moir Duncan and a book about Moir Duncan's life written by his family members Jessie Duncan and Doreen Raymer entitled, "Lives Lived: Of Moir and Jessie Duncan". The Writings Related to Timothy Richard section mostly contains photocopies of articles from newspapers and journals related to Timothy Richard and China. Also included are books, pamphlets, and microfilm and microfiche containing information related to Timothy Richard's work in China.
Series, III, Eunice Johnson Papers, is divided into four subseries: Writings and Notes, Research Correspondence, Source Guides and Bibliographies, and Memorabilia and Photographs from the Shanxi University Centennial Celebration (1902-2002). Writings and Notes includes Eunice Johnson's dissertation for the University of Florida as well as other writings about Timothy Richard. Research Correspondence is arrnaged alphabetically by correspondent and includes correspondence with repositories and individuals contacted by Eunice Johnson in the course of her research on Timothy Richard. The Source Guides and Bibliographies are arranged alphabetically by title and they are primarily made up of photocopies of bibliographies from various sources and literature searches. Memorabilia and Photographs from the Shanxi University Centennial Celebration is comprised of collected material from the celebration which Eunice Johnson attended in May 2002.
Arrangement
I. Timothy Richard Correspondence and Writings, 1884-1918
II. Collected Research Resources, 1876-2007
III. Eunice Johnson Papers, 1867-2002
Missions -- China; Missionaries; Richard, Timothy, 1845-1919; Baptist Missionary Society -- China
- Timothy Richard Correspondence and Writings, 1884-1918; Series I
  - Correspondence, 1887-1918
    - Baptist Missionary Society, 1918 May 1 (Box 1, Folder 1)
    - Christian Literature Society for China, 1887, 1901-1915 (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Evans, Ben, 1916 Oct 14 (Box 1, Folder 3)
    - Horton, Dr., 1917 Oct 7 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Head of the Russian Church, 1917[?] May 28 (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - Ridge, W. Sheldon, 1915 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Smith, Arthur H., 1915 Oct 10 (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - Wainwright, J.L., 1909 Dec 8 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Writings, 1884-1918
    - Diaries and Notes, 1885-1918
      - Timothy Richard's Diary, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 9)
      - Timothy Richard's Diary, 1914 Dec-1915 Feb (Box 1, Folder 10)
      - Outline - How to get a higher class of missionaries for China, 1885 Jun (Box 1, Folder 11)
      - Order of Study in our religion, translation from Chinese by Timothy Richard, 1887 (Box 1, Folder 12)
      - Statement of Facts. Being the Report of the Sub-Committe on the Province of Shansi, 1887 Feb (Box 1, Folder 13)
      - Baptist Missionary Society. China Sub-Committee Meeting notes, 1893 Mar 16 (Box 1, Folder 14)
      - Peking Gazette (notes by TR on margins), 1902 Jul 3 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      - "War articles", 1916 (Box 1, Folder 16)
      - "A World Religion for a World's Peace.", 1917 May 28 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      - R.T.S. Speech, 1917 Jul 19 (Box 1, Folder 18)
      - Timothy Richard notes, ca.1917-1918 (Box 1, Folder 19)
      - Ancient Chinese Parables, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 20)
      - The Bringing of the Far East into the Kingdom, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 21)
      - Notes, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 22)
      - re. Peace, n.d. (Box 1, Folder 23)
    - Newspaper Clippings and Journal Articles, 1884-1918
      - "Christian Persecutions in China - Their Nature, Causes, Remedies", 1884 (Box 1, Folder 24)
      - "The Political Status of Missionaries and Native Christians in China", 1885 (Box 1, Folder 25)
      - "Fifteen Years' Missionary Work in China: An Address", 1885 Apr 30 (Box 1, Folder 26)
      - "Relation of Christian Missions to the Chinese Government", 1890 (Box 1, Folder 27)
      - "The Influence of Buddhism in China", 1890 Feb (Box 1, Folder 28)
      - "Historical Evidences of Christianity for China", 1890 Apr (Box 1, Folder 29)
      - "The Intellectual Benefits", 1890 May (Box 1, Folder 30)
      - "Political Benefits of Christianity", 1890 Oct (Box 1, Folder 31)
      - "The Social Benefits of Christianity", 1890 Nov (Box 1, Folder 32)
      - "Moral Benefits of Christianity", 1891 Jan (Box 1, Folder 33)
      - "The Spiritual Benefits of Christianity", 1891 Apr (Box 1, Folder 34)
      - "The Historical Evidences of Christianity - Present Benefits", 1891 Oct (Box 1, Folder 35)
      - "Scheme for the General Enlightenment of China", 1892 Mar (Box 1, Folder 36)
      - Letter - "S.D.K.", 1892 May (Box 1, Folder 37)
      - Book Review: "Peeps into China", 1892 Sep (Box 1, Folder 38)
      - "Appeal for Christian Work Among the Higher Classes of China", 1892 Nov (Box 1, Folder 39)
      - Synopsis/Introduction of "How to Awaken Faith in the Mahayana School", 1892-1893 (Box 1, Folder 40)
      - Address of Welcome, 1893 (Box 1, Folder 41)
      - "Education and Missions. (Another View.)", 1894 (Box 1, Folder 42)
      - "How to Multiply Trade in China", 1894 Mar 1 (Box 1, Folder 43)
      - "God's Various Methods of Blessing Mankind", 1894 Jun (Box 1, Folder 44)
      - "A Practical Plan for Education", 1894 Jun (Box 1, Folder 45)
      - "Murray's New Phonetic System of Writing Chinese Characters", 1894 Aug (Box 1, Folder 46)
      - "China's Appalling Need of Reform", 1894 Nov (Box 1, Folder 47)
      - Table of Contents - Wan Kwoh Kung Pao, 1894-1896 (Box 1, Folder 48)
      - Presentation Testament to the Empress-Dowager of China, 1895 Apr (Box 1, Folder 49)
      - "Missionaries in China", 1895 Nov (Box 1, Folder 50)
      - An Interview with the Rev. T. Richard, The Daily News, 1897 Aug 30 (Box 1, Folder 51)
      - North China Herald and Supreme Court and Consular Gazette, 1895-1896 (Box 1, Folder 52)
      - North China Herald and Supreme Court and Consular Gazette, 1898 (Box 2, Folder 1)
      - North China Herald and Supreme Court and Consular Gazette, 1899-1900 (Box 2, Folder 2)
      - North China Herald and Supreme Court and Consular Gazette, 1903 (Box 2, Folder 3)
      - North China Herald and Supreme Court and Consular Gazette, 1905-1906 (Box 2, Folder 4)
      - "Memorial to the Chinese Emperor on Christian Missions", The Peking and Tientsin Times, 1896 Mar (Box 2, Folder 5)
      - "Memorial to the Chinese Emperor on Christian Missions" (Translation), The Chinese Recorder, 1896 Apr (Box 2, Folder 6)
      - "Some Recollections of David Hill", 1897 (Box 2, Folder 7)
      - "The Crisis in China and How to Meet It", 1897 Mar (Box 2, Folder 8)
      - "Prospectus of a Society for Aiding China to Fall in with Right Principles of Universal Progress", 1897 Jul (Box 2, Folder 9)
      - "The Crisis in China and How to Meet It", 1898 Feb (Box 2, Folder 10)
      - "The China Problem Settled by the Universal Peace Union", 1898 Oct (Box 2, Folder 11)
      - "Non-Phonetic and Phonetic Systems of Writing Chinese", 1898 Nov (Box 2, Folder 12)
      - "Educational Problems of China", 1899 (Box 2, Folder 13)
      - "Universal Peace", 1899 Mar (Box 2, Folder 14)
      - "Suggestions for the World Mission Conference New York, 1900", 1899 Mar (Box 2, Folder 15)
      - "A League of Princes for the Promotion of Universal Peace", 1899 May (Box 2, Folder 16)
      - "The China Problem - A Solution", 1899 Aug 26 (Box 2, Folder 17)
      - "Pleas for Christian Literature, Ecumenical Missionary Conference", 1900 (Box 2, Folder 18)
      - "Reinforcements for the Christian Literature Society for China", 1900 Mar (Box 2, Folder 19)
      - "Christian Literature", 1900 Dec (Box 2, Folder 20)
      - "In Memoriam of Rev. Alexander Williamson, LL.D.", 1901 Feb (Box 2, Folder 21)
      - "Educational Work Indispensable", 1901 Feb (Box 2, Folder 22)
      - "One Great Missionary Secret", 1901 Mar (Box 2, Folder 23)
      - "An Appeal to Missionaries for Books Suitable for Mandarins", 1901 Apr 29 (Box 2, Folder 24)
      - "Some New Conditions of Missionary Work in Pacified China", 1901 Apr 30 (Box 2, Folder 25)
      - "How a Few Men May Make a Million Converts", 1901 Jun (Box 2, Folder 26)
      - Translation of Proclamation Issued by Ts'en Governor of Shan-si, on the 29th day of the 8th moon, 27th year of Kuang-hsu (11th October, 1901)., 1901 Oct 11 (Box 2, Folder 27)
      - Letter - "Missionary Help Sorely Needed", 1902 Mar (Box 2, Folder 28)
      - "Christian Literature for China", 1902 May (Box 2, Folder 29)
      - "The Outlook for Christianity in China", 1902 May (Box 2, Folder 30)
      - "Of More Value than a Thousand Missionaries", 1903 Jan (Box 2, Folder 31)
      - "The New Education in China", 1903 Jan (Box 2, Folder 32)
      - "Some Features of Educational Reform in China", 1903 Jan 7 (Box 2, Folder 33)
      - "The Religion of the Future", 1903 Jan 21 (Box 2, Folder 34)
      - "The Toleration Question Again", 1903 Mar 5 (Box 2, Folder 35)
      - "The Shansi University from Within", 1903 Apr (Box 2, Folder 36)
      - "Better than Thousand New Missionaries", 1903 Apr (Box 2, Folder 37)
      - "Christian Literature in India", 1903 Jun (Box 2, Folder 38)
      - "Timothy Richard's Relations with the Chinese Government and the Christian Church", 1903 Dec (Box 2, Folder 39)
      - "The Forces which are Molding the Future of China", 1904 Feb (Box 2, Folder 40)
      - "Appeal to the Arthington Committee", 1904 Mar 15 (Box 2, Folder 41)
      - "Correspondence. China Mission Statistics.", 1904 Nov (Box 2, Folder 42)
      - "Introduction, Life in West China", 1905 (Box 2, Folder 43)
      - "The Great Peace. A Suggestion", 1905 Jan (Box 2, Folder 44)
      - "A Great Chinese Missionary. Interview with Dr. Timothy Richard". British Weekly, 1905 Feb 2 (Box 2, Folder 45)
      - "Thirty-five Years in China. A Talk with Rev. Timothy Richard." Christian World, 1905 Feb 2 (Box 2, Folder 46)
      - Interview. The Baptist Times, 1905 Feb 3 (Box 2, Folder 47)
      - Interview. "Thirty-six Years' Labour in China", 1905 Feb 22 (Box 2, Folder 48)
      - Speech of Dr. Richard, at the Thirteenth Annual Meeting, held in Edinburgh, on 17th March, 1905, 1905 Mar 17 (Box 2, Folder 49)
      - "The China Problem from a Missionary Point of View", 1905 May (Box 2, Folder 50)
      - "What the Bible is Doing in China", 1905 May 3 (Box 3, Folder 1)
      - Talk - Annual Meeting of the British and Foreign Bible Society, 1905 May 5 (Box 3, Folder 2)
      - "The China Problem from a Missionary Point of View", 1905 Jun (Box 3, Folder 3)
      - Talk - Annual Meeting of the Friends of Missions in Leeds, 1905 Jun 16 (Box 3, Folder 4)
      - "Dr. Richard on China: A Conversation", 1905 Jul 20 (Box 3, Folder 5)
      - "Three Surprising Facts", 1905 Sep 15 (Box 3, Folder 6)
      - "In Memoriam: Miss Marietta Melvin", 1905 Nov (Box 3, Folder 7)
      - "World Imperialism or Universal Defence on Peace Principles", 1905 Dec (Box 3, Folder 8)
      - "Is There a Yellow Peril?" [Interview with Timothy Richard, Bristol], ca.1906 (Box 3, Folder 9)
      - "Anglo-Chinese Union", ca.1906 (Box 3, Folder 10)
      - "The Church of the Future", 1906 Jan 15 (Box 3, Folder 11)
      - "China and the West", 1906 May (Box 3, Folder 12)
      - "The Coming Event - A World Empire", 1906 Oct (Box 3, Folder 13)
      - Most of the Circulars Sent Out In Behalf of the Diffusion Society and the Christian Literature Society Between 1891-1901, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 14)
      - "Conversion by the Million", 1907 (Box 3, Folder 15)
      - "Some of the Greatest Needs of Christian Missions", 1907 Apr (Box 3, Folder 16)
      - "The Chinese Recorder", 1907 Aug (Box 3, Folder 17)
      - "Conversion by the Million", 1907 Oct (Box 3, Folder 18)
      - "Some of the Problems of Life in New China: Abstract of a Lecture", 1908 (Box 3, Folder 19)
      - "Taith Genhadol Ddiweddar yn China", 1908 Oct (Box 3, Folder 20)
      - "A Missionary Visit to Korea", 1908 Dec 31 (Box 3, Folder 21)
      - "Present National Movements", 1909 Jan 14 (Box 3, Folder 22)
      - "Kang Yu-wei", 1909 Jan 25 (Box 3, Folder 23)
      - Letter to the Editor: "The Doctrine of Reciprocity", 1909 Apr 23 (Box 3, Folder 24)
      - "Better than Dreadnoughts", 1909 May (Box 3, Folder 25)
      - "Doctor Timothy Richard on China", 1909 Jun 10 (Box 3, Folder 26)
      - "Civilizations Tested", 1909 Sep 30 (Box 3, Folder 27)
      - "The Late Prince Ito", 1909 Oct, Nov (Box 3, Folder 28)
      - "Future of China", 1910 (Box 3, Folder 29)
      - "The China Giant Awake", 1910 Oct 13 (Box 3, Folder 30)
      - "History's Turning Point: Dr. Timothy Richard's Advice", 1910 Oct 13 (Box 3, Folder 31)
      - "A Turning Point in Human History", 1910 Oct 14 (Box 3, Folder 32)
      - "The Outlook in China", 1911 Jan 12 (Box 3, Folder 33)
      - "Some Remarks on the Foregoing Paper", 1911 Jun (Box 3, Folder 34)
      - "The Race Congress I and II", 1911 Oct, 1911 Nov (Box 3, Folder 35)
      - "In Memoriam. Dr. Griffith John"., 1912 (Box 3, Folder 36)
      - "A Striking Event in Japanese Religious History", 1912 Jan (Box 3, Folder 37)
      - "Religion and Civilization", 1912 Jan 6 (Box 3, Folder 38)
      - "The Future of the Educational Association", 1912 Apr (Box 3, Folder 39)
      - "Universal Religion Needed Says Dr. Timothy Richard", 1912 Jun (Box 3, Folder 40)
      - "The Future of the Church in China", 1912 Nov (Box 3, Folder 41)
      - "Confucianism and China: The Reports of Reaction", 1914 Jan 20 (Box 3, Folder 42)
      - "Some Aspects of Buddhist Art: Lecture by Dr. Timothy Richard", 1914 Nov 6 (Box 3, Folder 43)
      - "How to End Militarism and War", 1915 Mar 17 (Box 3, Folder 44)
      - "Monarchy, Yes: Dr. Timothy Richards [sic] on China's Problems", 1915 Aug 29 (Box 3, Folder 45)
      - "A Plan of Peace with Goodwill that has Never Failed", 1916 Sep 4 (Box 3, Folder 46)
      - "The Awakening of China: Interview of Timothy Richard", 1916 Nov 8 (Box 3, Folder 47)
      - "Some Forces in Modern China", 1916 Dec (Box 3, Folder 48)
      - "Great Openings for Women's Work in China", 1917 (Box 3, Folder 49)
      - "The Beginning of Permanent Peace: Out of the Melting Pot", 1917 Sep 13 (Box 3, Folder 50)
      - "Proposal for the Formation of a League of Religions", 1918 dec 7 (Box 3, Folder 51)
      - "Appeal for the Enlightenment of the Higher Classes of China", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 52)
      - "Flying Machine Plans", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 53)
      - "The Religious Problem of East and West" (Box 3, Folder 54)
      - "Some of the Greatest Needs of Christian Missions", n.d. (Box 3, Folder 55)
    - Pamphlets, 1885-1900
      - Wanted: Good Samaritans, Baptist Missionary Society, 1885 (Box 3, Folder 56)
      - China Mission Handbook Circular, Mar 1894 (Box 3, Folder 57)
      - Christian Literature: Its Extent and Value with Special Reference to China, and Its Bearing on the World, 1900 (Box 3, Folder 58)
      - A Scheme for Mission Work in China, n.d. (Box 3, Folder 59)
    - Books, 1905-1916
      - Some Hints for Rising Statesmen [photocopy], 1905 (Box 3, Folder 60)
      - The Awakening of Faith: In the Mahayana Doctrine-The New Buddhism by the Patriarch Ashvagosha. Translated into English in 1894 by Rev. Timothy Richard, 1907 (Box 3, Folder 61)
      - The Awakening of Faith by Ashvagosha, Translated by Timothy Richard [photocopy], 1910 (Box 3, Folder 62)
      - Conversion by the million in China: being biographies and articles. Vol. I. Shanghai: Christian Literature Society [photocopy], 1907 (Box 4, Folder 1)
      - Conversion by the million in China: being biographies and articles. Vol.II. Shanghai: Christian Literature Society [photocopy], 1907 (Box 4, Folder 2)
      - The New Testament of Higher Buddhism, T. & T. Clark, 1910 (Box 4, Folder 2a)
      - Historical Evidences of Christianity, Commercial Press, Ltd., 1911 (Box 4, Folder 3)
      - A Dictionary of Philosophical Terms: Chiefly from the Japanese, by Dr. Timothy Richard and Dr. D. MacGillivray, Christian Literature Society for China, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 4)
      - A Mission to Heaven: A Great Chinese Epic and Allegory, by Ch'iu Ch'ang Ch'un, Translated by Timothy Richard, Christian Literature Society [photocopy], 1913 (Box 5, Folder 1)
      - Calendar of the Gods in China, Commercial Press Limited [photocopy], 1916 (Box 5, Folder 2)
      - An Epistle to All Buddhists throughout the World [photocopy], 1916 (Box 5, Folder 3)
      - Forty-five Years in China: Reminiscences by Timothy Richard, D.D., Litt.D., Frederick A. Stokes Company [photocopy], 1916 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Collected Research Resources, 1876-2007; Series II
  - Related to Mary Richard (wife of Timothy Richard), 1887-1903
    - "Sketch of Dr. Richard's career since coming to Shanxi," by Mary Richard, 1887 May 11 (Box 5, Folder 5)
    - "Chinese Music," by Mary Richard, 1890 Aug (Box 5, Folder 6)
    - "The Life of the 'Goddess of Mercy'", by Mary Richard, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 7)
    - "True Story of a Chinese Girl," by Mary Richard, 1897 (Box 5, Folder 8)
    - "The Martyrs of 'Young China'", by Mary Richard, 1899 (Box 5, Folder 9)
    - "EA of China, The Shanghai Chinese Girls' School", 1899 Apr (Box 5, Folder 10)
    - "The Christian and the Chinese Idea of Womanhood and How our Mission Schools may help to develop the Former Idea," by Mary Richard, 1900 Jan (Box 5, Folder 11)
    - Notes, The Chinese Recorder, Jun 1901 (Box 5, Folder 12)
    - "Chinese Music," by Mary Richard, 1902 (Box 5, Folder 13)
    - Mary Richard Obituaries and Memorials, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Related to Moir Duncan (colleague of Timothy Richard), 1876-2000
    - Transcriptions of letters written by Moir Duncan, 1876-1906 (Box 5, Folder 15)
    - Account of monies spent in Sh'en Hsi on famine relief, 1893-1894 (Box 5, Folder 16)
    - Shensi Mission Annual Report, 1894 (Box 5, Folder 17)
    - Birth Certificate for Dorothy Whitson Duncan, 1896 (Box 5, Folder 18)
    - Missionary Mail, Jan 1900 (Box 5, Folder 19)
    - Shansi Imperial University, Sep 1903 (Box 5, Folder 20)
    - Moir Duncan Information, 1903, 1906, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 21)
    - Moir Duncan Obituaries and Memorials, 1906 (Box 5, Folder 22)
    - Marriage certificate for Charles Kent Duff and Dorothy Whitson Duncan, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Scotland and the B.M.S. "Scots in China": Moir Duncan, 1942 (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - Moir Duncan Information from Jessie Duncan, n.d. (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Mrs. Moir Duncan, L.L.A., n.d. (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - Shansi Compound Plan (Box 5, Folder 27)
    - Duncan, Jessie and Doreen Raymer. Lives Lived: Of Moir and Jessie Duncan. Toronto: WindyRidge Books., 2000 (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Writings Related to Timothy Richard
    - Correspondence, Manuscripts, and Notes, 1916-1922
      - "A great and new opportunity for neutrals", 1916 Aug 11 (Box 6, Folder 1a)
      - Letter from Thomas Lewis to D. Wyre Lewis, 1920 Sep 23 (Box 6, Folder 2)
      - Letter from Evan Morgan to Thomas Lewis, 1921 Feb 1 (Box 6, Folder 3)
      - Letter from Thomas Lewis to D. Wyre Lewis, 1921 May 13 (Box 6, Folder 4)
      - Letter from William E. Soothill to H. Bowser, 1922 Oct 6 (Box 6, Folder 5)
      - Report on the China Missions (Wilson and Fullerton) (Box 6, Folder 6)
      - Notes on his visit: Liang Chi Chao, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 7)
      - Poem: Nonsense, by H. Vernon Elliott, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 8)
      - Notes: Re the late Timothy Richard, China, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 9)
      - Timothy Richard, 1845-1919," by C.E. Wilson, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 10)
      - "Timothy Richard and the Christian Literature Society," by Evan Morgan (Box 6, Folder 11)
      - "Canmlyddiant Timothy Richard," by D. Wyre Lewis, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 12)
      - "Ei Denlu a Gantnef", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 13)
      - "Y Cymro yn China", n.d. (Box 6, Folder 14)
      - "Y Parch Timothy Richard, D.D., D.Lit., LL.D.," by W. Hopkyn Rees, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 15)
      - "Y Pench Timothy Richard," by H. Cernyar Williams, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 16)
      - Note: Timothy Richard, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 17)
      - Timothy Richard Information, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 18)
    - Newspaper Clippings, Articles, and Book Chapters, 1884-2000
      - "Christian Persecutions in China", 1884 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      - "Shantung: English Baptist Mission", 1891 (Box 6, Folder 20)
      - "The Hunan Tracts of China, which Produced the Anti-Christian and Anti-Foreign Riots of 1891, Analysed by a Shocked Friend and A Critical Digest of Indulgent Treatment of Foreigners, by China's True Friend", 1892 (Box 6, Folder 21)
      - "Is Christianity Worth Introducing into China?", 1893 (Box 6, Folder 22)
      - "Elementary Education Reform", 1895 Oct 11 (Box 6, Folder 23)
      - "A Scheme for Reform in China", 1896 Mar 20 (Box 6, Folder 24)
      - "New China and Its Leaders", 1898 (Box 6, Folder 25)
      - "Peace Congress", 1899 (Box 6, Folder 26)
      - "Shanghai Public Education for Chinese Scheme," North China Herald, 1899-1900 (Box 6, Folder 27)